Nav Shergill

QA Engineer at Venmo

navshergill88@gmail.com

Summary

I'm an experienced QA Engineer with a passion for creating excellent user experiences by increasing quality and improving engineering processes while working for such companies as Venmo, Granicus and Intel.

Throughout my career, I have been responsible for project management, performance metrics, and building test plans. While working for Venmo, a \$3.2B digital wallet company, I was the first Quality Engineer and the first engineer to test the app. As the Mobile QA Engineer, I must anticipate problems and provide resolution suggestions that fit budgetary requirements.

I have also worked as an IT Consultant where I took pride in meeting deadlines and providing on-site and offsite services to a variety of clients. My responsibilities included data collection, establishing security measures, and product delivery.

Experience

QA Engineer at Venmo

February 2015 - Present

Venmo is a free digital wallet that lets you make and share payments with friends. You can easily split the bill, cab fare, or much more. As Venmo's first mobile QA engineer, I work not only to ensure excellent product quality, but to develop and refine bug processes.

- Ensure users have the smoothest app experience possible by providing stable quality software.
- Partner with iOS and Android teams to verify releases go smoothly Improve our current testing approach and explore new solutions.
- Create, monitor, and communicate important metrics about the quality of the program.
- · Design, build and run automation test
- Redesigned JIRA bug reporting process and triage workflow
- Streamline processes with Engineers to solve build and deploy issues more efficiently.
- Mobile testing (iOS & Android).

QA Automation Engineer at Granicus, Inc.

October 2014 - February 2015 (5 months)

Granicus manages the world's largest and most reliable legislative content network—containing more than 5 million government media files and public records and maintaining a 99.98% uptime track-record. Granicus also has 63,000+ government users currently leveraging their technology to run successfully their day-to-day government information tasks including webcasting public meetings, managing and delivering legislative information, collaborating with citizens.

- Troubleshoot network and developed technical solutions for users around the country.
- Provided excellent customer service to all clients to address technical issues via email, phone, and other electronic mediums promptly.
- Documented procedures when identifying and resolving client issues via Salesforce CRM database.
- Assisted with the daily maintenance of web applications and a multi¬gigabit video streaming network, in addition to critically analyzing processes and procedures and recommending improvements.
- Provided training to clients in the use of Granicus systems and applications.
- Monitored the health of solutions using Proactive Systems Management tools.
- Maintained and modified web-based documents written in HTML/CSS & Smarty code.

Customer Care Engineer at Granicus, Inc.

April 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 6 months)

The Customer Care team supports a 400+ Government client base with any Granicus software or hardware issues. This includes remotely managing 1,400+ encoding servers and 500+ touch-screen based voting systems, as well as troubleshooting AV systems, LAN/WAN connectivity from client servers and PCs, Granicus applications on client PCs, and mobile devices/apps. Additional responsibilities included QA validation testing on all product suites, MySQL database management, IIS configuration, and video transcoding and conversions.

• Worked as part of a team to cover a rotating 24/7 shift in order to provide the highest level of customer service and satisfaction

Replication Engineer at Intel Corporation

2013 - 2013 (1 year)

Intel Corporation is one of the world's largest semiconductor chip makers. It is the inventor of the x86 series of microprocessors; the processors found in most personal computers. Intel supplies processors for computer system manufacturers such as Apple, Samsung, HP and Dell. Intel also makes motherboard chipsets, network interface controllers, and integrated circuits, flash memory, graphics chips, embedded processors and other devices related to communications and computing.

• Ensured the testability and manufacturability of integrated circuits.

- Optimized component production, and evaluated, developed and debugged sophisticated test methods.
- Worked with process technology development and product teams to help deliver the best process and design effective reliability models based on ROI, process limitations, Q&R requirements, and product usage models.

Internet Marketing Intern at Market Motive

March 2012 - June 2012 (4 months)

Market Motive helps marketers, agencies, and enterprise teams change their careers, lives, and businesses by providing the industry's most comprehensive digital marketing training.

- Conducted course video editing, graphic design, and marketing research projects.
- Utilized Google Adwords and analytics, web analytics
- Managed social media profile by using such systems as Hootsuite.

Quality Assurance Assistant - Internship at West Marine

October 2010 - March 2011 (6 months)

West Marine is a leader of boating-related product and gear for recreation on the water that provides outstanding value to every Customer.

- •Managed multiple software test case scenarios.
- •Tracked hardware and software bug reports for Software Engineers and provided process analysis and recommendations for improvement.
- •Provided technical support for Testing Team.
- •Created progress reports directly used by the CIO.

Computer Support Specialist

July 2006 - September 2010 (4 years 3 months)

- Operated system installation/repair with MS Windows.
- Installed and replaced computer components such as; CPU, video cards, power supplies, and motherboards.
- Troubleshooter for a variety of technology issues.
- Established and created security measures.
- Created data recovery for corrupt systems or near hard drive failures
- Assisted with password recovery, virus, trojan, and spyware removal.
- Offered technical support on-site or via phone.

Supplement Instruction Leader

June 2008 - May 2010 (2 years)

Instruction (SI) is an academic support program utilizing peer-assisted study sessions to assist students with traditionally difficult academic courses. SI sessions are an opportunity for students to

work together with other classmates to ask questions, prepare for examinations, compare notes, discuss readings, and develop organizational tools.

- •Facilitated approximately 3 SI sessions every week by using planned group work, collaborative activities, and active learning strategies.
- •Designed and lead study sessions on a regular basis.
- •Provided students with unique learning techniques based on learning style.

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz

Bachelor of Science, Cum laude, Technology and Information Management with Highest Honors, 2010 - 2012

Activities and Societies: Delta Sigma Pi, Experiential Leadership Program, Education Abroad Sweden, South Korea

Honors and Awards

Dean's Honors List: Fall 2011 - Spring 2012

Nav Shergill

QA Engineer at Venmo

navshergill88@gmail.com



Contact Nav on LinkedIn